Lewis Morgans

Senior Software Engineering Contractor

PERSONAL SUMMARY

My name is Lewis, I'm a senior software engineering contractor, working through my own company Swift Media to provide consultancy and software solutions to tech companies.

I'm experienced, dedicated and professional. I have provided software solutions to businesses working within finance, insurance, maritime counter piracy / smuggling operations and internal communications systems for domestic and foreignintelligence agencies, notably for the United States Pentagon and White House

In my spare time I enjoy coaching junior developers and testing my limits with emerging technologies and frameworks.

I work 100% remotely between the hours of 9AM and 5PM UK standard time. Outside IR35.

WORK HISTORY

SRT-Marine, Cardiff — Software Engineer[Contractor]

May 2021 - August 2021

GeoSync - Working alongside several software engineers in an Angular / Unity project, to produce a maritime tracking application. Capable of tracking all vessels within the Philippines, providing all information about the vessel and it's souls on board. GeoSync provides counter piracy and smuggling features in conjunction with emergency distress calls such as a man overboard, or an SOS notification. All being sent to several regional data centers in conjunction with the Philippine coast guard and maritime fishery agencies.

Dept Design Agency, Cardiff — Software Engineer[Contractor]

May 2021 - August 2021

Pearsons Education - Working within a team consisting of a mixture of front end, back end, designers and QA analysts to produce a contentful CMS driven web application. Utilising Angular 11, Docker, TailwindCSS and heavy implementation of contentful. Dynamic routing solutions and reusable angular components. Being a leading member of the front end development team and taking ownership of new features and defect resolution. We were able to produce a high quality project within a limited time frame to suit the clients needs and exceed their expectations.

HCL Technologies, Cardiff — Software Engineer[Contractor]

March 2021 - May 2021

Natwest mobile banking - Working alongside a mixture of front end and back end engineers to produce new features inside of Natwest's online banking platform. Utilising Angular 11, with heavy implementation of RxJs, NgRx and StencilJs. Recent features worked on being client accounts direct debits management, being able to sort through both active and inactive debits and allowing the end user to perform multiple actions depending on the state held within the NgRx store.

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/lewismorgan sengineer

PERSONAL WEBSITE:

www.weareswift.dev

GITHUB:

https://github.com/lewismorgans

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, SASS, Tailwind, JavaScript, JSX, TypeScript, TSX, Next.js, GIT, BitBucket, Jasmine, Jest, Karma, Docker, Angular 2+, Jenkins, ES6, REST API's, GraphQL, OOP/FP, RXJs, NgRx, Bootstrap 4.0, StoryBook, CI/CD.

SOFT SKILLS

JIRA, ClickUp, Confluence, Communication, Time management, AGILE/SCRUM, Project management, Knowledge transfer, Code reviews, coaching.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

VQ Communications, Cardiff — Software Engineer[Contractor]

September 2020 - November 2020

Conference Manager - Involved with the UI team working within an Angular framework to provide a bespoke communications dashboard. Creating friendly user interaction for call management, resting on top of a .NET core and Cisco bridge. Heavy implementation of NgRx state management and RxJs Observables providing a powerful and scalable code base for clients operating in a close system environment such as the American department of defence, the Pentagon, SOCOM, the White House and several unnamed intelligence agencies.

Swift Media, Cardiff— Development Director / Founder

March 2020 - Present

Admiral, Cardiff— Software Engineer

August 2018 - March 2020

InstaQuote; Involved in a large software delivery team with the target of reducing the customer journey time when applying for a home insurance quote. Opposed to 20 pages of information, we implemented a DVLA api to gather information about the clients home and repopulate the required quotation fields allowing the clients journey time to be cut dramatically, thus improving customer retention and overall sales. The application built within Angular 6 supported by a Java middle tier was my first project for Admiral.

QuoteEngine; Initially part of a small 4 man team, I was responsible with the code rewrite of the existing quote engine from a previous custom AngularJS implementation, to Angular 9. Starting as a proof of concept once we were able to prove the improved performance, efficiency and scalability of the new code base the team was then tripled in size to support a full rewrite. During this time we utilised state management NGRX and heavily leveraged the RXJS library. At my time of leaving the company the project was near it's completion with only automated testing remaining.

Keytree, Port Talbot—Software Engineer

February 2018 - August 2018

TravelSafe; Subcontracted to British Petroleum, I acted within a medium sized team to deliver a mobile application built in Angular 5, using Ionic Cordova for native mobile usage. TravelSafe was in its infancy during my time on the project, supporting things such as a panic button, sending your GPS location to the BP main office. Helpful tips, such as not entering certain parts of town, avoiding tap water in certain countries etc. Designed for BP employees to manage their physical safety whilst travelling for work.

Mythic Media, Cardiff— Software Engineer / Founder

June 2016 - February 2018

Digital Agency - Providing SPA's and web based applications to local business owners, music groups and freelance studios such as illustrators and photographers. Using TypeScript and the Angular 4 framework to provide a fast and scalable delivery service to clients.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Five, Three, Two, Go! — Software Engineer

Creation of a financial management application. Following the common budgeting practice known as the 50-30-20 rule, my application will allow users to register accounts, input their salaries and be met with an allowance of how much they can allocate to each section of the rule. The users can also input their actual expenditure and be notified by a seemingly pleasing UI of their over or under expenditure per section. The application is built within Angular v9 and supported via a Node/Express middle tier.

Pegasus — Software Engineer

Creation of a headless content management system. Using Angular 2 with a Node.JS backend to support persistent data through use of a user defined database link, such as MySQL, MongoDB etc.

GameShorts - Software Engineer

A web based video sharing application. Users can create and register accounts, upload videos, and share their game video libraries with friends. Currently in a stable Beta release for crowd testing and feedback. Designed as a place for gamers to share their favourite personal videos with a targeted audience.

EDUCATION

Cynffig Sixth Form College, Kenfig Hill

2008-2010 (A Level)

ICT

Business

Cynffig Comprehensive School, Kenfig Hill

2003-2010 (GCSE)

Maths
English Literature
English Language
Physics
Astro Physics
Chemistry
Design in digital applications